<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2016 | Tech jibber-jabbers]]></title>
  <link href="http://yusizhang.github.io/blog/categories/2016/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://yusizhang.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-28T10:56:14-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://yusizhang.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Yusi Zhang]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Project Yet Name Unknown]]></title>
    <link href="http://yusizhang.github.io/blog/2016/02/17/project-yet-name-unknown/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-17T21:17:34-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://yusizhang.github.io/blog/2016/02/17/project-yet-name-unknown</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some initial ideas about this project.</p>

<p>By the end of year 2015, I start to get my hands on some DevOps works by chance. It turns out pretty interesting. I am surprised, shamed that how little that I know of this area, and amazed by how fast the technology evolves. Puppet, Chef, MCollective, Docker&hellip;all these fancy terms make me so eager to put them on my LinkedIn profile, which ends with this open source idea. Well&hellip;I am not even sure about the term &ldquo;Open Source&rdquo; is legit in my case. I will probably just put all my codes and documentations somewhere on the Internet publicly and that&rsquo;s all.</p>

<p>Okay, back to the topic. I am thinking of building a dev to release style of pipeline to reduce the unnecessary distraction from non dev works by providing a sort of user friendly interface to inspect a vm&rsquo;s states. At least for the demo and testing purpose. I don&rsquo;t really see too much of actual enterprise level benefits from this project. More of self education purpose.</p>

<p>After couple hours of research, I come out this premature technology candidates:</p>

<ol>
<li>Container will be hosted by AWS Docker enabled environment.</li>
<li>Jenkins CI(Continuous Integration) Jobs will be triggered by github post commit actions.</li>
<li>Chef runs will be kicked by Jenkins job.</li>
<li>Possibly integrates with kitchen for Chef testing.</li>
</ol>


<p>Roughly saying, I want to give it like a 6 months plan. After first three months named stage one, I would want to be able show it to my team as my side project. So it may focus on a certain set of use cases. The last three months named stage two, I would want to focus on optimizing its scalability. And if goes well I can learn more feedback from the community if this project really worth taking a look at.</p>

<p>Stage one will do a one week sprint planning.
I will divide epics based on technology key word:</p>

<ol>
<li>AWS + Docker</li>
<li>Jenkins CI</li>
<li>Chef Kitchen testing</li>
</ol>


<h2>Sprint 02-17 ~ 02-24:</h2>

<ol>
<li><p>Learning 101 on AWS + Docker. Deliverable: re-open my aws account, set up a running instance, install docker.</p></li>
<li><p>Learning 101 on Jenkins. Deliverable: Install Jenkins on the docker image.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Git repo: <a href="https://github.com/YusiZhang/Project0">https://github.com/YusiZhang/Project0</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
